<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Cubs Fun Games</title>
    <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk" />
    <updated>2024-04-19T14:19:08+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Dave Bird</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk</id>

    <entry>
        <title>20.Scotch</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/20scotch.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/20scotch.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:19:08+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The players run around the hall and when they are running a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>The players run around the hall and when they are running a tennis ball is introduced into the mix. When a player catches the ball in their hands they shout ‘Scotch’. At this point all other players must freeze. The player with the ball in their hands can turn by pivoting on one foot but cannot move otherwise. They must throw the ball at someone and try and hit them to get them out. Once the ball has left the players hands all the other players can move again and dodge the ball being thrown at them. If a player is hit by the ball they are out.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>19.Pairs</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/19pairs.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/19pairs.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:18:58+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The players get into pairs. They must then run around the hall,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br>The players get into pairs. They must then run around the hall, away from their partners. When the whistle is blown they must find their partner, link arms backwards and sit down (with their arms still linked). The last pair to find each other and sit down are out.<br><br>Suitable for Beavers, Cubs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>18.Numbers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/18numbers.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/18numbers.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:18:45+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The players all run around the hall and when the leader shouts&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>The players all run around the hall and when the leader shouts a number, the players must get into groupings of that number. If players cannot make up a grouping of that number they are out.<br><br>Suitable for Beavers, Cubs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>17.Ship, Shore</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/17ship-shore.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/17ship-shore.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:18:36+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    One end of the hall is designated ship and one end is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>One end of the hall is designated ship and one end is designated shore. The leader shouts ship or shore and the players run to that end of the hall. The leader tries to catch the player out by, for example, pointing at ship when calling shore, or by calling ship when the players are already at ship. The last player to reach the end called or if a player moves from the end they are at when that end is called, is out. The leader introduces new concepts into the game such as:<br><br>− Captain’s Coming: The players must all stand to attention and make a salute sign. They must freeze as if the Captain is coming. If a player moves they are out.<br><br>− Sharks: The players must get themselves off the floor by what ever means necessary to avoid the sharks.<br><br>− Scrub the Decks: The players must drop to their knees and scrub the ground.<br><br>− Climb the Rigging: The players must make a ‘climbing up a ladder’ motion.<br><br>− Ballroom Dancing: The players must get into pairs and begin ballroom dancing. Suitable for Beavers</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>16.Tiny Island</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/16tiny-island.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/16tiny-island.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:18:23+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    A circle big enough for all the people playing is chalked in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br>A circle big enough for all the people playing is chalked in the centre of the hall. The players are split in half and each half is sent to a different end of the hall. When ‘Tiny Island’ is called by the leader, all the players must run into the chalked circle. When the leader counts down from five, each player must be fully in the circle (no feet or arms over the edge!). The circle gets smaller and smaller and players are knocked out as they cannot fit inside.<br><br>Suitable for Cubs, Scouts and Venture Scouts.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>15.Bench Ball</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/15bench-ball.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/15bench-ball.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:17:56+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This game involves patrol-sized teams. The object of the game is to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>This game involves patrol-sized teams. The object of the game is to score a goal by throwing the ball to your own goalie who is standing on a bench at the end of the hall. Each team has a goalie at either end of the hall. When they have the ball, players cannot move from the spot they are on, they must throw it to a team mate.<br><br>Suitable for Beavers, Cubs, Scouts and Venture Scouts.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>14.Pass Out</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/14pass-out.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/14pass-out.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:17:47+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    All the participants sit in a large circle and number off in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>All the participants sit in a large circle and number off in fours. When a number is called everyone with that number gets up and runs around the circle in the same direction. When someone is passed out by another player they are knocked out. The object is for one person to be left running around at the end. Then the game leader calls another and it continues.<br><br>Suitable for Beavers, Cubs, Scouts and Venture Scouts.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>13.1,2,3 Go</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/13123-go.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/13123-go.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:17:39+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The group is split in four and each one stands in a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>The group is split in four and each one stands in a corner. When one is called everyone runs width ways across the hall, then two is called everyone runs length ways and when three is called everyone runs diagonally. There should be plenty of confusion, it can be run as a knockout game. Suitable for Beavers, Cubs, Scouts and Venture Scouts</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>12.Ladders</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/12ladders.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/12ladders.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:17:22+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Everyone sits down in two lines opposite some one else. Every pair&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br>Everyone sits down in two lines opposite some one else. Every pair should have their feet touching. Each pair is given a number; when their u=number is called the pair stand up and run up between everyone’s legs (like a ladder) until they reach to the top, they then run on the outside to the end and up the middle again until they reach their place. The first of the pair who sits down gets a point for their side.<br><br>Suitable for Cubs, Scouts and Venture Scouts.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>11.Dice</title>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Bird</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/11dice.html"/>
        <id>https://www.cubsfun.co.uk/11dice.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-19T14:17:15+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Six squares are chalked on the floor and numbered from 1 –&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><br><br>Six squares are chalked on the floor and numbered from 1 – 6. All the players run around the room until the leader blows a whistle and then they choose a square and sit in it. The leader than throws a dice (preferably a large one) All the players in the chosen numbered square are out! And the game continues for there. It works better with large numbers.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
